James Gross NLRB Files /4057
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD 7/35-11/47
  - Sub-Series A. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD RECORDS
    - Sub-Series 2. CORRESPONDENCE 7/19/35-3/19/70
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        2/2/39-2/28/39; Alexander B. Hawes' comments on the Walsh Amendments; Witt's response to Louis Jaffee (University of Buffalo, School of Law) asserting the Board will not interfere in fights between affiliates of one organization; Feidelson's discussion of traditional southern congressmens' sentiment toward the Board; correspondence on the investigation and hearing in the Alston Coal Co. XVII-R-34 (8pp); Jeff Kibre's (Chairman, Motion Picture Technicians Committee) request that the Board take jurisdiction over Lowes, Inc. et al XXXI-C-864-871; John L. Lewis' and President's discussion of government contracts and renegade companies; Herrick's opposition to the investigation of her office; Eagan on Senate Bill 1392; P.E. Booth & Co. et al XX-R- 316-326 in connection with AFL-CIO controversy; Fahy's discussion of 8(1) violations and reinstatement order 8(3) in the Electric Vacuum Cleaner Co. et al VIII-C-73, VIII-R-15.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        3/1/39-3/30/39; Witt to Brenner concerning Nylander's speech and related correspondence; enforcement not recommended in the Sterling Electric Motors, C-415; John L. Lewis and the President correspondence; Blakenhorn on LaFollette Committee California investigation; James S. Rowe Jr. to the President about NLRB appointee; Gates' discussion of problems with the Cleveland office; Fahy to Lester F. Collins on ambiguity in the Fansteel decision; problem with SWOC in the International Nickel Co. Inc, R-640; correspondence concerning the American Bar Association Administrative Law Bill, S. 915.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        4/1/39-4/29/39; Phillip's reports on Senate Witnesses and related correspondence; John G. Shott's impressions of Milwaukee; correspondence relating to amendments; violations of 8(1),(2) and (5) in Inland Steel Co. C-252; unfair labor practices in Jacob Bros. Co. C-244; A.F.ofL. and ILA request injuction in the Shipowners Association of Pacific Coast et al R-638, R-572; investigation in the Milwaukee Publishing Co. R-953 (XII-R- 154); run-off election in the Consumers Power Co. R-1004; Jackson on the Waterman Steamship Corp. vs NLRB; Witt on free speech; Russel A. Nixon's (Harvard University, Dept. of Economics) request to be heard at Senate hearings; Blakenhorn's discussion of Board participation in the LaFollette-Thomas Bill hearings; Howard Myers' list of cases to which A.F.of L. might raise objections; William Green's "The Case for the Individual Form of Labor Organization".
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        5/1/39-5/31/39; Correspondence concerning reconsideration of enforcement in the Sterling Electric Motors Inc. C-415; cases that may be cited by the A.F.ofL.; Bowen's account of a bitter fight between factions of the U.A.W.A.; the Post Intelligencer hearings; regional office problems with the Thompson case; Davidow and Madden conversation about Chrysler Co. cases; the administrative Law Bill; the appointment of William Leiserson to replace Donald Wakefield Smith, includes 32 pp statement from Donald Wakefield Smith before the Committee on Education and Labor and amendments.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
        6/1/39-6/29/39; Correspondence reporting on the conduct of the ballot in the International Nickel Co. R-640; Feidelson's discussion of Googe's testimony; the sit-down strike at Indianapolis Glove Co. C-251; Mary T. Norton concerning proposals to amend the NLRA and related correspondence; Blakenhorn regarding the LaFollette-Thomas Bill Report; R.D. Winstead on espionage and provocation in Mid-Continent Petroleum Corp. and Cosden Pipeline Co. XVI-C-353 (6pp); the disestablishment of a company union in the Douglas Aircraft Co. UAW Local 214 C-268.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        7/1/39-7/31/39; Correspondence reporting on the CIO contract in the Morgan Packing Co. cases; question of contempt action against companies in connection with Consolidated Edison Co. of New York, Inc.; application for certiorari in the Sands Mfg. case; Rosseter's explanation of the increase in number of cases going to hearing and decrease in cases closed and related correspondence (30pp+); Leiserson's dissent in the Chrysler cases; irregularities in procedure in the Todd-Johnson Dry Docks R-754, and the American Can Co. R-1177, R-1178; Blakenhorn's notes on documentation of the steel organizing movement in 1934 (confidential); Witt's and David Dubinsky's (Pres., I.L.G.W.U.) discussion of the Alpena Garment Co. R-1366.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        8/1/39-8/28/39; Correspondence reporting on supervision of regional offices; informal agreement between the Reconstruction Finance Corp. and the NLRB; discrimination in the Columbia Pictures Corp. XXI-R-621 et al; list of investigating committee personnel (Smith); Congressman Smith's wish to meet with the Board; Leiserson's refusal to act in the Todd-Johnson and Celanese Corp. cases, and his contention that the Clyde- Mallory Lines case (R-1329) was mishandled, and his observation that the Board wobbled over policies in the Western Union Case R-1415, and his reminder to the Board to get the facts straight in the Hazel Atlus Glass case (C-233); appellate litigation relating to the Republic Steel and Sterling Electric Motors Inc. cases; investigation in the Frost Rubber Works XIII-C-1058 (10pp); Grenville Stark (American Bar Association, Committee on the Bill of Rights) to Fahy on alleged violations of the First Amendment; Martin R. Kurasch's discussion of the congressional investigating committee (15pp).
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        9/5/39-9/30/39; Correspondence reporting on the extension of the operation of the NLRA in Puerto Rico and the apppointment of a Board representative to Puerto Rico; jurisdiction in the Weyerhaeuser Timber Co. R-1315 thru 1317; correspondence between the Attorney General and Madden regarding emergency planning; Fahy's cooperation with Grenville Clark's Committee; Blakenhorn's discussion of: cooperation with the Senate Civil Liberties Committee, the scope of the California Committee and the NLRB and public opinion; Fahy's and Edmund M. Toland's (General Counsel, Special Committee to Investigate the NLRB - the Smith Committee) discussion of information requested and related issues; Maurice W. Howard's dismissal; Toland's refusal to permit inquiry into cases in which he acted as counsel (includes Jones and Laughlin); Smith Committee's questionaire sent to unions; Leiserson's call for an investigation of San Francisco Office; Leiserson's impatience in the Cornbleet Bros. case (XI-C499); Los Angeles Office's problems; trial practice; regional attorneys' and directors' questions to Fahy, regarding the Smith Committee.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        10/2/39-10/28/39; Correspondence concerning Allen Rosenberg's description of the strange behavior of Smith Committee investigators Robb and Smith; Homer Martin's attack on the 7th Region Office (12pp); Bendix Products Corp. and the Pattern Makers Association of South Bend and the Bendix Industrial Police Association; Toland's requested list of memoranda; Tilford Dudley's disqualification; tenative anaylsis of NLRB memoranda on Interstate Commerce; enforcement in the Swift and Co. C-923; memo to Toland concerning special consideration in the Harlan County Miners case; Emerson's claim of unfair conduct in the Clyde-Mallory Lines case (R-1329); Fahy's discussion of representation and complaint cases; Smith Committee's request for correspondence relating to the LaFollette Committee; Toland's and Robb's discussion of Pratt's files and the Los Angeles Office; Leiserson's dissent on run-off elections.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 30)
        11/1/39-11/15/39; Correspondence concerning Fred H. Brown's (Comptroller General of the U.S.) discussion of the Hugh C. McCarthy settlement (7pp); the Legal Survey Committee's procedural report (15pp); Pressman`s discussion of the Mt. Vernon Car Co.; Smith Committee's request for information from the Review Staff; a biographical sketch of Madden; regional directors' opposition to Toland's request; A.F.of L.'s intention to take Waterman S.S. Co. C-375 to the Supreme Court; a list of law schools from which the law staff is drawn.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 31)
        11/16/39-11/29/39; Correspondence concerning Board memoranda which might be questioned by the Smith Committee (23pp); Walsh's personal files; Fahy's and Witt's discussion of 9(c) cases (13pp); Fahy's and Toland's discussion of the Seattle office.
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        12/1/39-12/31/39; Correspondence relating to enforcement in the Schwarze Electric Co. C-409; Saposs' material for the House Investigation; Ferguson's (Smith Committee) and Rhoda Rastoff's discussion; Padway's and Charles E. Hughes' (Chief Justice. U.S. Supreme Court) discussion of Rice's "Law and Contemporary Problems"; Robert L. Condon's (NLRB Union) discussion of automatic wage increases; Anti-Dies contribution; Dubinsky's and Witt's discussion of the Alpena Garment Co. case; Toland`s dismissal of Ferguson; affidavit concerning James P. Millis' testimony; Smith Committee`s request for the Review Attorneys' files; Phillips' discussion of activities of Smith Committee members; list of personnel detailed by the NLRB to Senate Civil Liberties Committee and related tables.
      - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        1/2/40-4/29/40; Correspondence reporting on Board procedure in the Morgan cases; back-pay in the Jacobs Bros. Co. Inc. C-244; the use of economic material in Westinghouse C-1241; failure to bargain in the Libby-Owen Ford Glass Co. XI-C-931; Saposs' talk on the history of the labor movement; letters to Davis Lawrence (U.S. News) and Wesley W. Stout (The Saturday Evening Post) regarding Empire Furniture Corp.; mal- administration of region 21; Smith Committee testimonies of William Green, Theodore H. Freter; Madden, N.S. Clark, Boettiger and others; Thomas D'Alesandro Jr.'s (3rd District Maryland) request for executive advice on the labor situation from the President; Reilly's discussion of Bernard Donahue's personal files; Phillips and the F.B.I. investigation; charges of violating the secrecy of income tax returns against the Board (7pp); the power of governmental agencies to require prospective contractors and borrowers to comply with the laws of the U.S.
      - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        5/1/40-8/31/40; Correspondence concerning Patrick J. Taft's (attorney) analysis of Smith Committee's recommendations for amending the NLRA (13pp); refund of WPA earnings in the Republic Steel Corp. C-184; Leiserson's dismissal of the Harker-Beauman and Co. R-1851; reinstatement in the New York Times C-775; Philip Murray's (Chairman, SWOC) and the President's discussion of NLRB appropriation; Perkin on public and family welfare (6pp); Lewis to Hillman (Commissioner, Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense) discussing government policy; correspondence to the President about Madden; Isadore Lubin (Commissioner of Labor Statistics) on the confidential nature of the Bureau's files; Blakenhorn's examination of the Smith Committee Material; Madden to the President on the present status of the NLRA (4pp.)
      - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        9/5/40-12/30/40; Correspondence reporting on the Longshoremen's situation; NLRB versus Ford; the Smith Committee including a request for a list of employees belonging to the American League for Peace and Democracy; information on Harry Bridges; allegations to the effect that Marie Prince is an active communist; Perkins to Early about Madden; Edwin S. Smith to Bland discussing the ILWU (6pp); Weiner's verson of his telephone conversation with Vogt (10pp); Harry Millis' chairmanship; the President's and Samuel I. Rosenman's discussion of the Flint Strike and the appeasement of Hitler; Millis (Chairman, NLRB) to F.J. Bailey (Assistant Director, the Executive Office of The President, Bureau of Budget) about H.R.6324 (5pp); Watts to William J. Shaughnessy (Associate General Counsel, House Committee to Investigate the NLRB) regarding exhibits; Witt's resignation as Secretary; the employers' right to free speech; budget revision; litigation and petitions for certiorari.
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        1/10/41-2/28/41; Correspondence reporting on discriminatory layoffs in the Columbia Box Board Mills Inc. II-C-2942; unfair policy with respect to run-off elections in the Elk Tanning Co. R-1941; W.K. Jordan (General Editor, University of Chicago Press) to Millis regarding Prof. Harold W. Dawey's Administrative Procedure and Practice of the NLRB; budgetary difficulities; reclassification policy proposed by the NLRB Union; field coordinators and personnel; agreement between the NLRB and the Lawyers' Union of the NLRB; analysis of H.R. 3489; alleged shifting and promotion of trial examiners.
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        3/1/41-6/28/41; Correspondence relating to NLRB versus Ford and free speech; Leiserson's reorganization; the handling of complaints under Sec. 9(A) of the Hatch Act; H.R. 4637 (7pp); trial examiners and budget; Wirin's resignation; agreement with the NLRB Union; changes in mid-west regional offices; the budget; appointment of William H. Davis and P. Graham to the National Defense Mediation Board; memo for the Solicitor General from Edward F. Prichard Jr. (Special Assistant to the Attorney General) discussing an interagency mechanism for setting issues of labor policy; the Board's request to be listed as a defense agency.
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        7/11/41-12/13/41; Correspondence reporting on the investigation in the Monsieur Henri Wines Ltd. case II-C-3465 (6pp); decertification in the American Fruit Growers Co. et al R-666 thru R-699; H.R.5314; questionable re-appointment of Edwin S. Smith; Joseph Curran and Saul Mills' (President and Secretary of the Greater New York Industrial Union Council) discussion of Elinore Herrick; Herrick on the "Witt Regime"; the requisition of certain NLRB records by the Archivist of the U.S.; Millis' and Mark Ethridge's (Chariman, President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice) discussion of grievance cases in which discrimination because of race, color or national origin, is alleged; tables on expeditures and field staff.
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        1/15/42-4/30/42; Correspondence relating to agricultural workers and the NLRA; administration of the Wisconsin Employment Relations Act and NLRA (14pp); the NLRB Union; objection to the appointment of Kathryn B. Harrell to the position of Chief of Dockets, Files and Mails; the Efficiency Rating Committee of the NLRB Union; the Kaiser Co. Inc.; formulation of National Labor Policy; Millis and War Department correspondence.
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        5/2/42-6/25/42; Correspondence relating to the Board committee on efficiency ratings and the union; relations with the National War Labor Board (NWLB) (9pp); the National Mediation Board; correspondence between Millis and the Comptroller of the U.S. discussing a survey of problems of American Small Business; letter and charts describing organizational structure.
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        7/8/42-12/29/42; Correspondence pertaining to FBI investigation of Gerard D. Reilly; the Ordinance Dept. (which supervises munitions plants); recruitment; the War Shipping Administration; NWLB; application of the NLRA to civil engineers; personnel; reports of Leiserson's resignation; analysis of opinion in the Southern Bell Telephone and Telegraph Co. versus NLRB (7pp); correspondence between John Green and the President regarding the Oregon Shipbuilding Corp. and the Kaiser Co. Inc. cases.
      - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        1/2/43-6/25/43; Correspondence concerning NLRN/NWLB relations; the War Labor Disputes Act cases (25pp); Budget Circular No.408; personnel; closing of the Indianapolis office; charts comparing cases; John Green, William Green, the President and Millis correspondence relating to the Kaiser Co. Inc. and the Oregon Shipbuilding Corp. cases.
      - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        7/6/43-12/28/43; Correspondence relating to the War Labor Disputes Act (Public Law 89, 78th Congress); the Connally Act sec. 8; Public Law 49, 78th Congress; H.R.327; alleged problems between the Board's organization and functions of staff; discharge of Floris Schick in the North American Aviation, Inc. 16-C-935 (7pp); question of jurisdiction between the NLRB and the NWLB in the Hughes Tool Co. 16-C-1018.
      - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        1/8/44-6/30/44; Correspondence reporting NLRB protests NWLB action in the May Dept. Stores Co. (Famous-Barr Co.); Padway's discussion of principles governing the "question of representation", and "unit appropriate for bargaining" (8pp) attached letter to Tobin; proposed restatement of principles (5pp); Lucile Woodward's request to remain in Indianapolis; Millis to Warren (Comptroller of the U.S.) regarding appropriations for the Dept. of Labor, Federal Security Agency and Independent Agencies.
      - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        7/6/44-12/30/44; Correspondence concerning comptroller ruling in the Briggs situation; dissolution of company dominated union in the Baltimore Transit Co. 5-R-1629, 5-R-1635; discrimination based on race or national origin in the Carter Mfg. Co. 15-R-1232; wildcat strike in the Draper Co, C-2553; breach of settlement agreement in the Midwest Piping and Supply Co. Inc. and United Steel Workers of America 14-C-882; Administrative Intern Program; R.H. Epperson's (President, Independent Metal Workers Union, Local No.1) and Hon. Robert L. Patterson's (Undersecretary of War) discussion of army seizure of the Hughes Tool Company.
      - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        1/1/45-6/29/45; Correspondence pertaining to the joint handling of representation questions; the 1944 Appropriation Act (19pp); NLRB statement to bargaining employees of the Western Union Telegraph Co.; conference between the N.Y. State Labor Relations Board and the NLRB (9pp); alleged 8(3) discharge of foremen; Harold D. Smith (Executive Office of the President, Bureau of Budget) to Millis about employees covered under Public Law 47, 78th Congress; F.J. Bailey (Assistant Director, Legislative Reference, Bureau of Budget) concerning H.R. 180 and H.R. 499; George W. Taylor and Millis correspondence regarding the Chicago Transformer case.
      - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        7/4/45-12/19/45; Correspondence reporting on coverage of agricultural workers under the NLRA; Dorothy L. Craig (President, NLRB Union, Local 14) to Isadore Greenberg demanding a union contract; Secretary of Agriculture to Paul Herzog (Chairman, NLRB) on the canneries' dispute; Robert P. Patterson (Secretary of War) to Herzog regarding elections among Mahattan Project employees; Robert H. Keys (President, Foreman's Association of America) to President Harry S. Truman about Board policy; the NWLB; end of war problems; current strikes; absorption of the Board into the Labor Dept.; change in rules concerning representation cases.
      - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
        1/16/46-6/26/46; Correspondence from Herzog to James E. Murray (Chairman, Committee on Education and Labor, U.S. Senate) discussing S.1661; to Hon. Harold D. Smith (Director, Bureau of Budget) about the Reorganization Act of 1945; to Jack Z. Anderson (House of Representatives) on the California Cannery situation; to Senator Alexander Smith concerning redefinition of the term "agricultural laborer;" to Lloyd Garrison about Sec. 8(5); to others discussing H.R. 4908 and 1947 appropriations; violations of 8(1), (5) in the J.I. Case Co. 13-C-2741; the Bercut Richards, et al 20-R-1414; the Wallace Corp. C-2321; Gerard Reilly to Joseph P. McMurray (Senate Committee on Education and Labor) with proposed amendment to prohibit secondary boycotts; to Hon. Harold D. Smith about H.R. 4934; U.S. Senate, Special Committee Investigating the National Defense Program requests information on operations and personnel.
      - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 17)
        7/2/46-12/16/46; Correspondence relating to the Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corp. and Bethlehem Steel Co.; the Administrative Procedure Act (7pp) and Committee; procedure in representation cases; Herzog to President Harry Truman recommending a bi-partisan policy on labor relations; suggestions for inclusion in his State of the Union Address; draft of letter (not sent) about appropriations; correspondence between E.E. Kirkpatrick (Colonel, War Dept., Corps of Engineers, Deputy District Engineer) and Herzog concerning East Tennessee staff.
      - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
        1/7/47-1/12/26/47; Correspondence reporting on Sec. 10 of the bill restricting the right to strike; the right of the NLRB to enter into a written agreement with the NLRB Union (26pp); deficiency appropriation; Herzog to Alexander Wiley (Chairman, Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. Senate) regarding Admin. Practitioners Act (?) (6pp); to J. Parnell Thomas (Chairman, House Committee on Un-American Activities) concerning support of communists; Donn N. Bent's (Executive Secretary and Chairman, Loyalty Committee) and Blakenhorn's discussion of Michael Komaroff; the San Francisco Directorship; the Craft Unit Proviso of the NLRA; Blakenhorn's discussion of enforcement of the Taft-Ives-Hartley Law.
      - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        1/8/48-12/22/48; Correspondence pertaining to the NLRB Union.
      - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 20)
        1/26/49-12/29/49; Correspondence concerning the the NLRB move into the Labor Dept.; hearing examiners' register; promotion policy; personnel.
      - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        1/30/50-9/11/50; Correspondence relating to the New York Act; the Harry Bennett Story.
      - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 22)
        1/29/51-8/23/51; Correspondence reporting on Union proposals; promotions; journeyman grade for legal assistants; suggested guide for effective relationships with organized groups in the Federal service.
      - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 23)
        6/2/52-6/19/52; Correspondence concerning production statistics; grievance; appointment of Assistant Executive secretary.
      - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        3/31/53-12/4/53; Correspondence between Herzog and Martin P. Durbin (Secretary of Labor) on separation of functions; memo of understanding from the NLRB Union; correspondence from Robert Johnson (President, NLRB Union).
      - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        2/19/54-7/9/54; Correspondence pertaining to the relationship between the NLRB Union and the Board; promotion policy; employee relations policy.
      - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        6/12/55; Blakenhorn correspondence including The Ford Way.
      - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        3/23/56; NLRB Local 10 with attached promotion policy.
      - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
        10/19/61; Research projects and resumption by the NLRB of research activity.
      - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 29)